或许那就是为什么Symmington太太
Perhaps that's why Mrs Symmington
不敢把信给他看吧
was afraid to show him the letter.
天啊 Burton先生
Good heavens, Mr Burton,
你真的以为不真实的诽谤
do you seriously think any woman would swallow cyanide
会让一个女人服毒自尽吗
if the accusations weren't true?
清白的女人会一笑而过
An innocent woman would laugh it off,
将之抛在脑后 要是我...我会这么做
throw it away. That's what I...I would do.
我们都会有自己的事业 Burton先生
We should all have a career, Mr Burton.
我想当医生 但我爸妈完全听不进去
I wanted to be a doctor, but my parents wouldn't hear of it.
- 不好意思 - 噢 没事
- I'm sorry. - Oh, don't be.
我觉得我是个非常幸福的人 再见
I'm one of the happiest people I know. Toodle-oo!
早上好 Burton小姐 希望你不会无聊
Good morning, Miss Burton. Not finding it too dull, I hope.
完全不会
Hardly.
看
Look.
你这淫荡的贱人 赶紧滚蛋
You painted trollop, go back to your bastard child.
很好
Nice.
非常好
Very nice indeed.
是的 这些单词是从旧书上剪下来的
Yes. The words have been cut from an old book.
我猜测是19世纪早期的
Early 19th century, I'd guess.
凶手很谨慎 戴了手套
Probably no fingerprints distinctive
所以并没有指纹留下
in the letters as the culprit is very careful to wear gloves.
信封上的字是用这个
Now, the envelope was typed on this.
Windsor Seven打印机打上去的
A Windsor Seven typewriter
所以字母A和D才不在一条直线上
with the letters A and D out of alignment.
这打印机谁的
So, who does it belong to?
妇女协会的
The Women's Institute.
是Galbraith办公室捐出来的旧款
It's an old model donated by the office of Galbraith,
Galbraith和Symmington
Galbraith and Symmington.
- 所以 可能是... - 没错 他们中的任何一个
- So, it could be... - Yes. Any one of them.
妇女们经常去那 先生
The ladies are always in there, sir.
摸摸看 你就知道了 先生
You can probably tell by the touch, sir,
是用一根手指打出来的
that was typed with one finger.
所以应该是个不习惯打印的人
So, it's someone not used to typing?
或许恰恰相反 他不想被认出来
Or somebody who is, but doesn't want us to know.
很有趣
Well, that's interesting.
怎么了
What is?
Burton的U好像是从A变过来的
The U in Burton seems to have been changed from an A,
或许她确实不擅长打印
Perhaps she's not such a good typist after all.
也有可能比我们想象的要更聪明
Or maybe cleverer than we think.
- 我想知道她怎么想的 - 谁知道呢
- I wonder how she feels? - Who knows?
这个小玩意儿要送回去
But this little beauty is going back.
记住我的话
And mark my words,
常在河边走 哪有不湿鞋
the pitcher will go to the well once too often.
- 可以聊一聊吗 先生 - 怎么了 Partridge
- Can I have a word, sir? - What is it, Partridge?
- 有关Agnes的 先生 - 噢 怎么了
- That was Agnes, sir. - Oh, yes?
她以前在这当过女佣
She was in service here.
她从孤儿院里出来的
And coming from the orphanage,
她很乐意和我聊天
she's gotten happy to talking to me
因此我可以和她说很多道理
so I could tell her what's what, you see.
说重点 Partridge
Get to the point, Partridge.
她现在为Symmingtons工作
Well, she works for the Symmingtons now
我想知道你允不允许她下午来这儿
and I wonder if you might give your permission for her
和我喝喝茶
to come to tea with me this afternoon.
她今天休假
It's her day off
她好像心事重重的 看上去很苦恼
and she's got something on her mind. She seems a bit of upset.
当然可以
Yes, of course.
谢谢 先生
Thank you, sir.
我得回家了
I must go home.
- 什么 - 今天
- What? - Today.
今天 为什么
Today? Why?
非常感谢你们能让我在这待着
It's been awfully good of you having me.
希望没打扰到你们
I expect I've been a fearful nuisance.
在这儿过得很开心 真的
I have enjoyed it awfully, really I have,
现在我必须回去了 毕竟 那才是我的家
only, now I must go back because after all, it is my home.
我不可能永远在逃避
I can't stay away forever.
再见
Bye.
今天和Barton太太过得不错 Partridge
We had a lovely tea with Miss Barton, Partridge.
那很不错 小姐
Pleased to hear it, Miss.
你和Agatha过得怎么样
How was yours with Agatha?
Agnes 小姐
Agnes, Miss.
- 对对 就是那个 - 她没来 小姐
- That's the one. - She didn't turn up, Miss.
- 噢 不好意思 - 没关系
- Oh, I am sorry. - Doesn't matter to me.
那就好
Good.
她约我见面 但爽约了
She wanted to meet and then she didn't show,
还一句道歉都没有
and not a word of apology either.
可能身体不舒服吧
Perhaps she's not well.
但也有可能她没什么教养
And perhaps she's just ill-mannered.
怎么了
What is the matter?
真受不了你闷闷不乐的样子
I've never been able to bear it when you sulk.
我没有闷闷不乐 - 你就是闷闷不乐
- I'm not sulking. - You are sulking.
Megan走了你就开始闷闷不乐了
You've been sulking since Megan left.
事实上 你还是小孩的时候就成天闷闷不乐的
In fact, you've been sulking ever since you were a child.
- 我没有 - 你有
- I haven't. - You have.
你今天不高兴 明天不高兴
You were sulky then and you're sulky now.
你就是那样的
You're the sulky type.
我想喝一杯
I could do with a drink.
或许能让我开心点
Might cheer me up.
那为什么不来一杯呢
Then, why don't you have one?
我会的
I might just do that.
行 想喝多少就喝多少吧
Fine. Have as many as you want,
然后喝到你都不知道自己是谁了
and when you're so drunk you can't remember who you are,
骑着你的摩托一头撞死得了
Then why not go for a spin and this time make damn sure!
那是个意外
It was an accident.
你就是个无药可救的骗子 真可悲
You're a hopeless liar. It's really quite pathetic!
我就是不开心 就酗酒了
So, I'm sulky, I'm a drunk
而且连说谎都不会 那又怎么了...
and I can't even lie properly. Is it any wonder that...
什么 Jerry 那又怎么了
What, Jerry? Is what any wonder?
有什么关系吗
What does it matter?
你怎么能这么做
How could you do it?
如果那是你认为的
If that's what you want to believe...
你以为那不伤我的心吗?
How could you think it wouldn't break my heart?
看到你这么绝望 我伤透了心
It breaks my heart now to think you could feel so wretched.
这真的太讽刺了
You know, it strikes me as the most extraordinary irony
你好像举着旗子胜利了
that you managed to survive the war with such flying colours,
但并没有真正找到了内心的平静
yet seem to find the peace so utterly defeating.
骂得很爽吧
Ghastly dump, isn't it?
我们可以回到过去
We could always go back.
抛弃所有的乐趣?
And miss all the fun?
你知道吗 Symmington太太去世
Do you know, it's exactly a week ago
都有一礼拜了
since Mrs Symmington's death?
警方应该已经有线索了吧
You'd think the police would have something by now.
指纹或者其他什么东西
A fingerprint or something.
- 是一周以前吗 - 嗯
- Exactly a week ago? - Mm-hm.
仆人们每周有一天假 是吗?
Maids have one day off a week, don't they?
是的
Yes.
都是同一天吗
The same day every week?
通常是这样的
That's the usual sort of thing. Apparently.
那么 刚好是一周之前
So, exactly a week ago,
Symmington是一个人在家里
Mrs Symmington was alone in the house
因为那天仆人都休假了
because it was the maids' day off.
我觉得事情很难水落石出
I'm afraid the penny's refusing to drop.
Megan?
她应该去和Partridge喝茶的
She was supposed to come to tea with Partridge,
但并没有出现
but didn't turn up.
为什么你注意到这个了呢
Why would that be of particular concern to you?
我不确定 我就是觉得不太对劲儿
I'm not sure. I felt uneasy for some reason or other.
现在要从每个细节中寻找线索
With every cause, it now transpires.
你有很强的直觉 Burton先生
You have sensitive antennae, Mr Burton.
你也是 Marple小姐 灵光一闪 对吗
So do you, Miss Marple. Just passing, were you?
噢 Burton先生
Oh, Mr Burton.
Holland小姐 我想知道 Megan还好吧
Miss Holland, I was wondering, is Megan all right?
她躺下休息了
She's having a lie-down.
- Burton先生 - 不好意思
- Mr Burton? - Sorry.
你知道Agnes有和Partridge说了什么吗
Did Agnes say anything to Partridge,do you know?
她太焦虑了
She'd have been far too anxious
在电话里什么也没说 探长
to divulge anything over the telephone, Inspector.
谢谢 Marple小姐
Thank you, Miss Marple.
Agnes通常会在午餐后出去走走
Agnes normally went out after lunch.
但事实证明她没离开过
It appears she never left,
因为你找到她的时候她还穿着工作服
because she was wearing her apron and cap when you found her
知道死亡时间吗
Any idea of the time of death?
是的 八点到十点半之间
Yes, between 8.00 and 10.30.
怎么被杀的
And how was she killed?
利器重击后脑
Sharp blow to the back of the head,
接着叉子直穿颅骨
followed by a skewer in the base of the skull.
天呐
Good God!
太可怕了
Quite appalling, isn't it?
- 但为什么 -我们可能永远不知道
- But why? - Well, we may never know exactly,
但我们可以猜测一下
but we can make a guess.
她或许知道了些什么
Well, she knew something, didn't she?
说的没错
That would be a fair assumption, yes.
Symmington太太死的那天中午
On the afternoon that Mrs Symmington died,
两个仆人本该出去的
when the two maids were supposed to be out,
但Agnes她提前回来了
Agnes, she came back rather early.
她有个男朋友
You see, she has a boyfriend.
渔船上的Freddy Firbank
Freddy Firbank from the fish shop.
是的 就在那天中午
Yes, and on that particular afternoon
他们一见面就吵了一架
they had a row when they first met.
我猜是年轻的Firbank收到了一封信
I gather that young Firbank received a letter
信里说Agnes脚踩两只船
suggesting that Agnes had other fish to fry.
但还有些疑点
But there is something else.
Symmington收到的那封信
The letter Mrs Symmington received
是没盖邮戳的
was never actually posted.
只是做出被投递的假象
It was faked to make it look as though it was posted,
邮递员下午送信之前
but it was pushed through this letterbox here
这封信已经被投到邮箱里了
before the afternoon delivery.
我的推断是Agnes在这往窗外看
My guess is Agnes was looking through the window here
等着他男朋友来道歉
waiting for her boyfriend to come and apologise...
看到了凶手来送信
And saw the culprit deliver the letter.
完全正确
Exactly.
但凶手是怎么知道她在家的呢
But how would the letter writer know that she was home?
或许是巧合吧 Burton先生
Well, it's a kind of miracle, Mr Burton,
事情究竟是如何发生的
how things get around this place.
我可能错了 当然 呃
I may be wrong, of course, but erm...
看上去很简单 不是吗
Temptingly simple, isn't it?
但是请告诉我 探长
But tell me, Inspector,
如果Agnes知道谁是凶手
if Agnes knew who the letter writer was,
我想知道为什么她什么也没说
then why, I wonder, didn't she say something?
Holland小姐
Miss Holland.
Burton先生
Mr Burton.
不好意思 我不是故意...
I'm sorry. I didn't mean...
我不知道我怎么了
I don't know what's come over me.
应该是被吓到了
I think it's the shock.
- 太残忍了 -可怜的姑娘
- Pretty grim, isn't it? - That poor girl.
被杀的可能是我们中的任何一个人
Just think, it could have been any of us,
甚至那两个小天使
even those two little angels,
像塔里的王子一样在床上被杀
murdered in their beds like princes in the tower.
Burton先生 这太可怕了
The awful thing, Mr Burton,
昨日中午
is that yesterday afternoon
我们和Symmington先生在教室里喝茶
we were having tea with Mr Symmington up in the schoolroom
就在那时候 Burton先生 那个可怜的女孩儿
and all the time, Mr Burton, that poor girl was
被人像渡渡鸟一样塞进橱柜里
squashed into that cupboard, dead as a dodo.
谢谢
Thank you.
那上周是什么情况 Holland小姐
And what about the other week, Miss Holland?
你可以叫我Elsie
You can call me Elsie, you know.
好
Right.
不好意思 你问了什么
I'm sorry, what did you ask?
- 上周发生什么事了 - Symmington太太出事的那天...
- What happened last week? - The day Mrs Symmington...
是的
Yes.
她一直有午休的习惯
Well, she always rested after lunch, you see.